the modern world depends on electricity
现代世界依赖电力
it's not just a luxury we use to power
这不仅仅是我们用来供电的奢侈品
our devices and enjoy our free time
我们的设备，享受我们的空闲时间
it's not even just the convenience of having light
这不仅仅是有光的便利
heating and cooling in our buildings
我们建筑物的供暖和制冷
electricity is a crucial resource
电力是至关重要的资源
especially in urban areas
尤其是在城市地区
providing public security
提供公共安全
safety and health
安全卫生
and making possible everything from emergency
并使从紧急情况到一切成为可能
response to modern medical care in hospitals
医院对现代医疗的反应
to even the other utilities we require like
甚至我们需要的其他公用事业，比如
fresh water and sanitation systems
淡水和卫生系统
but unlike those other utilities
但与其他公用事业不同
electricity can't be created
电是无法产生的
stored and used at a later time
稍后存储和使用
the instant it's produced  it's used
一旦生产出来，它就会被使用
no matter how far away the producer is from the user
不管生产者离用户有多远
and the infrastructure that makes all this
以及制造这一切的基础设施
possible is one of humanity's most important
可能是人类最重要的
and fascinating engineering achievements
和迷人的工程成就
hey I'm Grady and this is practical engineering
嘿，我是格雷迪，这是实用工程
on today's episode we're talking about the power grid
在今天的节目中，我们将讨论电网
this video is sponsored by nordvpn
本视频由nordvpn赞助
visit nordvpn
访问nordvpn
com slash practicalengineering to
com斜杠practicalengineering
get 75% off a three year plan
三年计划可享受75%的折扣
more on that later
稍后再谈。
like most people you probably
像大多数人一样，你可能
take the grid for granted
认为格子是理所当然的
electrical infrastructure is so ubiquitous
电力基础设施无处不在
it's easy not to notice that most of our power grid
很容易忽略我们电网的大部分
is out in the open for anyone to have a look
是公开的，任何人都可以看一看
I happen to be one of those people
我碰巧就是那种人
who does want to have a look
谁确实想看看
and hopefully by the end of this video
希望在这段视频结束时
series on electrical infrastructure
电力基础设施系列
you will be too
你也会的
this video is geared toward North America
这个视频面向北美
but most of the concepts will apply
但大多数概念都适用
to any other part of the world
到世界的任何其他地方
and just to give you a sense of scale
让你们感受一下规模。
there are only four distinct electrical grids
只有四个不同的电网
that service essentially all of North America
这项服务基本上覆盖了整个北美
you have the two big ones western and eastern
你有两个大的西部和东部
and the two electrical separatists Quebec and Texas
以及魁北克和德克萨斯两个电气分离主义者
depending on your definition
根据您的定义
an electrical grid can be considered
可以考虑电网
one of the world's largest machines  so
世界上最大的机器之一
how does this machine work
这台机器是如何工作的？
the basic function of generating electricity and
发电的基本功能和
delivering it to those who need it may seem simple
把它送给那些需要它的人可能看起来很简单
I can hook up a small generator to
我可以连接一个小型发电机
a light and boom power grid
轻型和繁荣的电网
with the cost of solar panels reaching record lows
随着太阳能电池板的成本达到历史新低
many are exploring the possibility of
许多人正在探索
generating all the power they need at home
在家里提供所需的电力
and forgoing the grid altogether
并完全放弃网格
but a wide area interconnection that's the
但广域互连就是
technical term for power grid offers some serious
电网的技术术语提供了一些严重的
advantages in exchange for increased complexity
以优势换取复杂性的增加
here's a simplified diagram showing the
这是一个简化的图表
major components of a typical power grid
典型电网的主要组成部分
and we'll follow the flow of electrical
我们将跟随电流的流动
current as it makes its way through each one
电流穿过每一个
we start with generation where
我们从哪一代开始
the electricity is produced
电力产生了
there are many types of power plants
有许多类型的发电厂
each with their own distinct
每个都有自己独特的
advantages and disadvantages
优点和缺点
but they all have one thing in common
但他们都有一个共同点
they take one kind of energy and
它们需要一种能量
convert it into electrical energy
将其转化为电能
most power plants are located away from
大多数发电厂都远离
populated areas so that electricity they
人口稠密的地区
create needs to be efficiently transported
创造需要高效运输
that's handled by high voltage transmission lines
由高压输电线路控制
at the plant
在工厂
transformers boost the voltage to minimize
变压器提高电压以最小化
losses within these lines as electricity
这些线路内的损耗作为电力
makes its way to the areas that need it
把它带到需要它的地方
once it reaches populated areas
一旦到达人口稠密地区
transformers then step down the power back
然后变压器停止供电
to a safer and more practical voltage
更安全、更实用的电压
this is done at a substation which also has
这是在一个变电站完成的
equipment to regulate the quality of electricity
调节电力质量的设备
and breakers to isolate potential faults
和断路器以隔离潜在故障
some energy customers draw power
一些能源客户汲取权力
directly from the transmission lines
直接从输电线路
but most are served from feeder lines
但大多数都是由支线提供的
that carry power from the substation
从变电站输送电力
this part of the system is called distribution
系统的这一部分称为分配
from the feeders
来自喂食者
smaller transformers step down the
小型变压器降级
voltage to its final level for industrial
电压到其最终水平，用于工业
commercial or residential uses before the
商业或住宅用途
electricity reaches its final destination
电力到达最终目的地
rather than a constant flow of current in a
而不是恒定的电流
single direction called direct current or DC
称为直流或直流的单向
the vast majority of the power grid uses
绝大多数电网使用
alternating current or AC where the direction
交流电或交流电方向
of voltage and current are constantly switching
的电压和电流不断切换
60 times per second in North America
在北美每秒60次
the major advantage of AC power is that it's
交流电源的主要优点是
easy to step up or down voltages
易于升压或降压
a critical part of efficiently and safely
高效安全的关键部分
moving electricity from producer to consumer
将电力从生产者转移到消费者
the device that performs this important
执行此重要操作的设备
role called a transformer is as simple as a
称为变压器的角色就像
pair of coils next to one another
一对紧挨着的线圈
a varying voltage in one coil induces a
一个线圈中的电压变化会引起
voltage in the other coil proportional to
另一个线圈中的电压正比于
the number of turns in each one
每一个的转数
if the current doesn't vary like in direct
如果电流不直接变化
current the transformer can't do any transforming
电流变压器不能做任何变换
it's helpful to think of the grid as a marketplace
将电网视为市场会有所帮助
power producers bring their electricity to the
电力生产商将他们的电力输送到
market by connecting to the power grid
通过连接电网进行市场
and power consumers purchase that
电力消费者购买它
electricity for use in their home or business
家庭或企业使用的电力
the economics and politics of the grid are
电网的经济和政治是
so much more complicated than this
比这复杂多了
but the important part of the analogy is that in
但是这个类比的重要部分是
many ways the power grid is a shared resource
电网在许多方面都是共享资源
because of that
正因为如此
it needs organizations to oversee and establish
它需要组织来监督和建立
rules about how each participant in the producing
关于生产中每个参与者如何
transmitting and consuming of power may use it
电力的输送和消耗可能会使用它
and there are three overarching technical goals that
有三个总体技术目标
engineers use to design and maintain the power grid
工程师用来设计和维护电网
the first one is power quality
第一个是电能质量
our electrical devices and equipment are
我们的电气设备和设备是
designed assuming that the power coming
设计假设电力来了
from the grid has certain parameters
来自网格有一定的参数
mainly that the voltage and
主要是电压和
frequency are correct and stable
频率正确稳定
some devices even count the oscillations in
有些设备甚至将振荡计算在内
the AC grid power to keep track of time
交流电网电源跟踪时间
so it's critical that grid frequency not deviate
所以电网频率不能偏离
changes in voltage can lead to brownouts or
电压变化可能导致断电或
surges that damage connected equipment
损坏连接设备的浪涌
one of the benefits of large power
大功率的好处之一
grids is electrical inertia
电网是电惯性
all those huge spinning generators connected
所有那些巨大的旋转发电机都连接在一起
together provide momentum that smooths out the
共同提供动力，使
ripples and spikes that can occur from equipment
设备可能产生的涟漪和尖峰
faults or quickly changing electrical loads
故障或快速变化的电气负载
the next technical goal of the grid is reliability
电网的下一个技术目标是可靠性
if like most people
如果像大多数人一样
you take the constant
你取常数
availability of power for granted
权力的可得性
that's by design
那是设计好的
much of the grid's complexity comes from how we
网格的复杂性很大程度上来自于我们如何
manage faults and provide redundancy so that you're
管理故障并提供冗余，以便您
rarely faced with blackout conditions
很少面临停电的情况
it's another inherent benefit of a grid
这是网格的另一个内在好处
that electricity can be rerouted when a
电力可以在
piece of equipment is out of service
一件设备停止使用
whether it was planned or otherwise
不管是不是计划好的
the final goal of the power grid is
电网的最终目标是
simply that the supply meet the demand
只要供应满足需求
electricity production and
电力生产和
consumption happen on a real time basis
消费是实时发生的
that means if it's plugged in
这意味着如果它插入电源
the light from the screen you're watching right
你看到的屏幕上的光对吗？
now was a drop of water in a turbine or a breeze
现在是涡轮机中的一滴水或微风
across a windmill just microseconds ago
就在几微秒前穿过风车
and by the way
顺便说一句
did you call your utility and let them know
你打电话给你的公用事业公司让他们知道了吗？
that you were going to be turning on your
你要打开你的
computer or phone to watch this video
电脑或手机观看此视频
I'm willing to bet you didn't
我敢打赌你没有
which means not only did they have to adjust
这意味着他们不仅要调整
their production up to match the extra load
他们的生产以匹配额外的负载
but they had to do it immediately
但他们必须立即这样做
without any warning whatsoever
没有任何警告
luckily having millions of people connected to the same
幸运的是，有数百万人连接到同一个
grid smooths out the demand created by individuals
网格平滑了个人创造的需求
but load following is still a major challenge
但负载跟踪仍然是一个主要挑战
for the most part
在很大程度上
electrical demand follows a fairly consistent pattern
电力需求遵循相当一致的模式
but factors like extreme weather can
但是像极端天气这样的因素可以
make it difficult to forecast
难以预测
grid operators balance demand by
电网运营商通过以下方式平衡需求
dispatching generation capacity in real time
实时调度发电能力
the cheapest sources of power are used to
最便宜的能源被用来
fulfill the base load that's more consistent
实现更一致的基本负载
and higher cost sources are used for
和更高成本的来源用于
peaking when demand exceeds the base
需求超过基数时达到顶峰
but it's not as simple as flipping on a switch
但这并不像打开开关那么简单
large power plants can take hours
大型发电厂可能需要数小时
days or even weeks to start up and shut down
几天甚至几周的时间来启动和关闭
equipment needs to be taken out
设备需要取出
of service for maintenance
维修服务
fuel costs fluctuate
燃料成本波动
renewable sources like wind and solar can have
风能和太阳能等可再生能源
massive and unpredictable variations in capacity
容量的巨大且不可预测的变化
providing irregular sloshes of power to the grid
向电网提供不规则的电力
you can see why balancing electricity supply and
你可以看到为什么平衡电力供应和
demand is this fantastically complex job of
需求是一项极其复杂的工作
taking into account all these considerations
考虑到所有这些因素
some of which are predictable
有些是可以预测的
and some of which aren't
其中一些不是
that's part of the reason we're trying to
这也是我们试图
make the grid smarter by using software
使用软件使网格更智能
sensors and devices capable of
能够
communicating with each other
相互交流
on the supply side
在供给方面
this can allow computers and software to do what they
这可以让计算机和软件做他们
do best take in and process huge amounts of data to
最好接收和处理大量数据
help us make decisions about how to manage the grid
帮助我们决定如何管理网格
but a smart grid can also help
但智能电网也可以提供帮助
on the demand side as well
在需求方面也是如此
unlike most of the goods we buy
不像我们买的大多数商品
consumers don't have a keen understanding of power
消费者对权力没有敏锐的理解
how much we're using
我们用了多少
or how much it should cost
或者应该花多少钱？
depending on the time of day or year
取决于一天或一年中的时间
a smart grid can take away some of that
智能电网可以消除其中的一部分
obfuscation allowing us to make decisions about
混淆让我们能够做出决定
how we use electricity in our day to day lives
我们如何在日常生活中使用电力
ultimately  the smart grid can help us use and
最终，智能电网可以帮助我们使用和
take care of this huge machine
照顾好这台巨大的机器
this shared resource we call the power grid
这种共享资源我们称之为电网
more effectively and
更有效和
efficiently now and into the future
现在和未来高效
just like electricity
就像电一样
internet connectivity is a resource
互联网连接是一种资源
on which we depend more and more
我们越来越依赖它
I work on these videos in my spare time
我在业余时间制作这些视频
which means I'm connecting to all kinds of
这意味着我正在连接各种
sketchy networks wherever I happen to be
无论我在哪里，都有粗略的网络
that's why I use nordvpn
这就是我使用nordvpn的原因
a lot of people don't realize how
很多人都没意识到
vulnerable you can be when connecting to
连接时可能容易受到攻击
unsecured Wi Fi networks at coffee shops  airports
咖啡店机场的不安全无线网络
convention centers  etc
会议中心等
one stolen password can completely
一个被盗密码完全可以
mess up your finances or worse
搞砸你的财务或更糟
what I love best about nordvpn is that I don't
我最喜欢nordvpn的是我不喜欢
have to balance inconvenience with the possibility
必须平衡不便和可能性
of having my identity stolen or computer exposed
我的身份被盗或电脑暴露
to malware because it's so easy to use
恶意软件，因为它很容易使用
I just load the app
我只是加载应用程序
click connect and it's done
点击连接就完成了
there's no limit on bandwidth and
带宽没有限制
it works on all my devices
它适用于我所有的设备
I have insurance on my car in
我的车有保险
case I get into an accident
万一我出了事故
I lock the doors on my house in case of an intruder
我锁上门以防有人闯入
and I use nordvpn especially when I'm on public Wi Fi
我使用nordvpn，尤其是当我在公共无线网络上时
networks to protect myself against hackers and malware
保护自己免受黑客和恶意软件侵害的网络
if your privacy and security
如果您的隐私和安全
online is important to you
在线对您很重要
they're offering an awesome
他们提供了一个很棒的
discount to fans of the channel
频道粉丝折扣
visit nordvpn
访问nordvpn
com practicalengineering or click the link in the
compracticalengineering或点击链接
description below to get 75% off a three year plan
以下描述可享受三年计划75%的折扣
use promo code
使用促销代码
practicalengineering to get an extra month free
practicalengineering获得额外一个月的免费
thank you for watching
谢谢你的收看
and let me know what you think
让我知道你的想法